{"id":"2018_10","name":"","memoryVerse":"\"For the sake of his great name the Lord will not reject his people, because the Lord was pleased to make you his own.\" â€“ 1 Samuel 12:22","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2018_10_1","questionText":"1. Use this space to record how you have seen God's activity during the week. (How has He provided, answered, comforted, reconciled, guided, etc.?)","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_2","questionText":"2. What from the notes, lecture, group sharing or personal study impacted you most in the past week?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read 1 Samuel 16:1-13 with 15:34-35.\nGod directed Samuel to anoint David as the next king of Israel.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"16:1-13"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_10_3","questionText":"3. How did God address Samuel's sorrow and misgivings? What lesson(s) do you learn?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_4","questionText":"4. What insights did the Lord give Samuel as he considered Jesse's sons? How do those insights challenge, warn or impact you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_5","questionText":"5. What do you learn about the way God views people? How does this compare to what you value in yourself and others? (See also Psalm 44:21.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"44:21"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read 1 Samuel 16:14-23.\nNewly anointed David began to serve King Saul.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"16:14-23"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_10_6","questionText":"6. What happened to Saul? What might have been some reasons it occurred? (For help, see Deuteronomy 28:15, 28; 1 Samuel 15:16-29; Lamentations 3:39.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"28:15"},{"book":"Deuteronomy","verse":"28:28"},{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"15:16-29"},{"book":"Lamentations","verse":"3:39"}]},{"id":"2018_10_7","questionText":"7. How did God move David from the shepherd's fields to serving in the palace? What characteristics are evident in David as he served Saul?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_8","questionText":"8. Where and how has God called you to use the gifts He has given you?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 17:1-32.\nDavid arrived at the battleground and assessed the threat.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"17:1-32"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_10_9","questionText":"9. What threat did Saul and the Israelite army face? How did they respond?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_10","questionText":"10. How did Goliath taunt the Israelites? What was his idea to settle the battle?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_11","questionText":"11. How did David's perspective differ from his brothers' and the other soldiers'? What do their words and actions reveal about their belief in God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_12","questionText":"12. In your present circumstances, what do your words and actions reveal about your belief in God?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read 1 Samuel 17:33-58.\nThe Lord saved the Israelites through David's victory.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"17:33-58"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_10_13","questionText":"13. How did David's prior experiences of God's power give him courage to face this challenge? How does this help or encourage you?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_14","questionText":"14. How did David's actions and words to Saul, the Israelites and Goliath express his absolute confidence in God?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_15","questionText":"15. In what specific ways could you follow David's example in your own present circumstances?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2018_10_16","questionText":"16. From this passage, what similarities are there between David and Jesus Christ? (Use any Scripture reference.)","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review 1 Samuel 16-17.","readVerse":[{"book":"1 Samuel","verse":"16:1-17:999"}],"questions":[{"id":"2018_10_17","questionText":"17. What would you like to see God do in your life this week? People of the Promised Land I Lesson 10 \" www.bsfinternational.org AdQ (06.2018) \" 7 8 \" AdQ (06.2018) www.bsfinternational.org \" People of the Promised Land I Lesson 10","answer":"","quotes":[]}]}}}